Now.
Alaskan king salmon
look at it
i mean it's
absolutely beautiful.
It's the fish that every
chef loves cooking
but
to fill it them.
It's
it's an operation
now this someone's been gutted
and scaled really important never sought
to fill it the salmon with the scales on
because the nice one go through
the scales they're so tough so
get your fishmonger to gut
it and scale it so easy to do
so
to fill it it
i to butcher it you've
gotta maximize on the yield
you gotta maximize
eyes on the portions
and you cannot afford.
One wrong slip
every time i do this
even after twenty years
and thousands of salmon
i still get that
tingle that level of excitement
that i'm there to conquer
and to
maximize
eighteen twenty sometimes
twenty five portions of salmon
and hold up that carcass
with the head and the tail and
make sure there's
no flesh on that bone.
First off
raise a sharp knife.
So now.
I'm using a Japanese
knife a weighted handle.
Multilayered compressed brush stainless
steel refined knife that's just like razor
but
you need this fish to help you
fill it it Felicity basically means
taken off two Phillies is around fish
could be quick
because it's quite oily
as these fish sit out in
the heat it starts to release
oil which can become so
much more dangerous so.
Finishing flatfish is so
much easier around fish
you got your work cut out.
Tilt
the tail and the head
and push them together
that way when i slice in
the weight of the fish
pulls against my knife
and I've got that nice clean cut
all the way.
There's the top.
Check that there's
no scales left
even when we've
finished scanning the fish
brush
the skin back
to it's normal way
really important because.
It helps
the knife strokes.
So much cleaner
look
when the skin is roughly
that the cut will be rough
bring the skin back
and then.
Get your knife prepped
but
look where we're
going first up with Finn
and slice towards the head
straight through.
Without going
through that bone
then.
Feel the tip.
Of the knife across
the center of the carcass
and come out.
Every time we go
into that summon
we clean the knife.
And then
with your hand
pull back the skin
clean your knife
clean knife.
Makes a clean cup
go through.
A salmon tilt the knife
pressure
with your index finger on
and then run all the way
along come down that back.
Come down that back
do not lift out all the way
to the end
very carefully open up
that first cup or your thumb
run down the side
and look where you're going
that's
the midway point of the filet
don't break the salmon gently
gently
prise it back.
Let the knife do the work
either.
As bones
you wanna hear that noise.
Should be like butter
there my firm is behind
the tip i'm pushing
down i'm over the Ridge.
Twisting turning and
then just let the knife
do the work
my thumb.
Is the guide
now.
I come through there.
I'm lifting up the filet as
not to break the salmon
and i'm treated with the utmost respect
and my fingers are behind the blade
off.
From there
carefully lift up.
When it comes to the rib cage
gently pushed down on the ribs
not slicing through the bones
there you go.
Very carefully
find the ribcage
there's the cage.
Prize slice
prize
and slice
hands behind the Sam man
is all in long nice flowing.
Strokes for the
fish if so careful.
Through
what you've gone
through the rib cage.
Place it down.
Make sure that's off
lay the fish back on top
and then.
Make sure that knife.
Check.
Make sure that knife is over
and then
just very gently till the knife
forty five degrees
look at your thumb
and this gonna come shooting out
now right down through the back clean.
Beautiful.
Then.
Very carefully
as one side.
Of the salmon through
halfway there
now
hold the head of the fish
the knife
till under.
Up
and literally just let
the knife to the work
and the top of those bones
use the tip of the knife to cut
away.
Now
through to the tail
keep the knife tilted up.
And then
to the tail
up.
And then second slice goes in
you go through
the bones this time
and then literally lift up.
Holding the sail
pulling the head back
and take off that center bone.
Lifted up.
Any time the knife gets stuck
pull it out.
Slice through
and then literally.
Use the tip of the
knife the sharpest part.
Come through.
Now
finishing salmon.
Is like an art.
Before i could
practice on salmon.
Literally
to go through thousands of macro
if that up.
Come through.
During the summer
back onto the board.
Size of this thing.
Get comfortable with it lift up
the carcass.
Slice through.
And then.
Come off
at the top.
And that
is what you want.
A very thin.
Carcass of salmon
with hardly
any.
Flesh on there
and a real.
Great yield
every time i see the young cooks
break down a whole salmon
i try to explain them that every
time the salmon left on those bones
it's money in the bin.
What could we use this for
great for stocks vti latinos but
we cannot afford any
salmon on there because
every time there's a morsel
of salmon on there
we as a business
are losing money.
Now.
Looking at the
size
of this fill it
the secret narrows to clean up.
The actual
ends.
At the belly
of the summon this bit here
that's where it's at it's
fanciest really delicious
so tasty so come down.
Straight lines all the way in.
Now that there.
Is the belly.
The belly of families
featured on every top
Japanese restaurant's menu
it's delicious
isn't that raw.
Absolutely mindblowing
the flavor is incredibly
rich it's
it's oil's delicious
traditionally
especially in Kyoto they'll finish that
with a blowtorch sort of thirty seconds over
the top and it gives this
really nice cracking flavor
do not waste that that
is beautiful.
Now
when we come
to portion the salmon.
Getting control
look at the salmon
and start
trimming
as you go
remember
we don't want to see wastes
take a little slice of the tail
keep all these bits
absolutely crucial.
Slice down.
There.
And then you start formalizing.
Your portion.
The higher you go
up into the salmon.
Okay.
The thinner
you slice.
And what i'm doing now.
Is slicing my portions.
Beautifully done.
Exactly the same way.
After years of practice
you start to see.
An eight
to nine ounce filet of salmon
and so.
The more you move up
into the belly of the summon
the thinner
they go.
And like i said.
Doing this.
Immediately
quickly.
You get used to the feel
of eight ounce ten hours
it's the same with a
new York strip or ribeye
every portion.
Just cutting once.
We're not hacking
away so nice clean cut.
And then as i get
to the top of the salmon
look.
Get very
carefully
in
that the knife to the work
and then.
Briefly lay these out
when you come to the end.
Keep that belly on there
do not waste that
and then the final
portion of the head
top
and tail.
Fold it over.
And then.
That
is one side.
From there.
Take your second
filet.
And flip
over
and each time now
we're gonna match
what we've done.
Against those portions
so
you start off
with your tail.
Look with your eyes
measure
the width
and use your blade
sometimes you see
the width of the salmon
you get further into the middle
the portions become thinner because
the salmon portions much longer
so.
My tail.
The.
Look
we repeat the exercise.
On the other side now.
We match that up.
Each and every time.
Now.
I'm a belly person i'm the kind of
guy that absolutely loves that beautiful
richness that belly
also it's the bit that.
A lot of customers
tend to turn their nose
up against because
it looks the fattest
but is absolutely incredible
and.
It's the sort of chef's cut
that we never put on the menu
and the way that we
keep for the chefs.
From there.
Through.
Two four
one two three four.
I learned how to master this.
Whilst working in
Paris and being given
the responsibility
to put the fish as
it came through
but chefs found it
boring but for me
it's like a work of art
because each and every time
i got so excited.
And then
the final bit
top
and tail
and then
literally
trim it up.
And lo.
Now.
Out of that summon.
Two four six eight ten twelve fourteen
sixteen eighteen twenty twenty two twenty four
portions of salmon
work that out
forty five fifty
dollars a portion
cooked to perfection.
Is a dream and that's
how you get the yield.
Now
pin bony in
too many chefs start
pinpointing the salmon
was his whole therefore breaks
up i prefer cutting the portions first
and then.
Taking your tweezers
lifting a piece of salmon up.
Use your finger to pull back
you can just see
the bones rising there
take a
pair of tweezers
lift
and pull.
Now the secret here
several little pot of water
lightly.
Moisten.
Applies
grip
and pull out
drop into water huh.
Lift.
Hold
and pull out
that way.
There's no bones hiding
and you get every
little bone in there
but for me but Paul gently.
Just pops out.
Filling fish.
You've got to find.
Your peace in the
most amazing knife
in these a flexible blade.
The best Japanese knives
are number one
but
a great finishing knife
is like a great bony knife
you just need that flexibility
around the blade
don't go into that salmon
with a blade that cannot bend because
you need to manipulate around that carcass
of the salmon
and you cannot afford
one
bad move
occur cross that look
portions or even
pin bones are out
and is ready
for cooking.